{
  "title": "7.8",
  "definitions": {
    "QUAFF": {
      "word": "QUAFF",
      "phonetic": "(kwof)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to drink deeply </p><p>To QUAFF is to drink deeply and heartily, to drain a cup or glass. </p><p>“Falstaff QUAFFED the tankard of ale in one long swallow, then called for more.” </p><p>“The tired athlete QUAFFED the refreshing drink.” </p><p>“I knew you were thirsty, but I didn’t expect you to QUAFF the whole pitcher of lemonade.”</p>"
    },
    "CHOLERIC": {
      "word": "CHOLERIC",
      "phonetic": "(kol'-Q-rik)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">bad-tempered, irascible </p><p>In the Middle Ages, anger was thought to be caused by an excess of CHOLER, or yellow bile, in the body. The adjective CHOLERIC (see <i class=“def-ital\">-ic</i> under Suffixes) is used about people who are easily made angry, who have irritable or touchy dispositions. </p><p>“As he got older, Mr. Finn became CHOLERIC; he would fly into rages over small matters.” </p><p>“Jane’s CHOLERIC nature made her difficult to deal with.” </p><p>“The CHOLERIC patient became furious with the nurses when they wouldn’t cater to his every whim.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CHOLER, n.</p>"
    },
    "DULCET": {
      "word": "DULCET",
      "phonetic": "(duhl'-sit)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">sweet, melodious </p><p>DULCET comes from an Old French word meaning “sweet,” and originally meant “sweet to the taste” in English. Over time, however, its meaning changed to “sweet to the ear,” <i class=“def-ital\">melodious</i>. </p><p>“When the soldier was feverish, only the nurse’s DULCET voice could soothe him.” </p><p>“The flute, when played well, has a particularly DULCET sound.”</p>"
    },
    "OBSEQUIOUS": {
      "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
      "phonetic": "(ob-sE'-kwE-as)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">fawning, servile </p><p>OBSEQUIOUS means “excessively polite.” The word usually has a negative connotation and suggests flattery and groveling, although it may only suggest extreme obedience and attentiveness. </p><p>“The boss didn’t like OBSEQUIOUS employees who would constantly open doors for him and compliment his ideas.” </p><p>“The service at the restaurant was friendly but not OBSEQUIOUS.” </p><p>“The OBSEQUIOUS servants said that nothing would give them more pleasure than to do our bidding.” </p><p>Crafty is more popular than the correct answer—<i class=“def-ital\">fawning</i>—on the Pretest, perhaps because OBSEQUIOUS people often seem to be up to something with their insincere flattery; or <i class=“def-ital\">crafty</i> may be chosen because of confusion with the word <i class=“def-ital\">devious</i>.</p>"
    },
    "REMUNERATE": {
      "word": "REMUNERATE",
      "phonetic": "(ri-myU'-nQ-rAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to pay for, pay to </p><p>REMUNERATE is a somewhat formal synonym for <i class=“def-ital\">pay</i>. It is especially used about payments for services rendered or losses incurred. </p><p>“We offered to REMUNERATE them for the time they had spent helping us.” </p><p>“If you become my assistant I will REMUNERATE you handsomely.” </p><p>In a slightly different sense, REMUNERATE can mean to <i class=“def-ital\">pay for</i> or to <i class=“def-ital\">reward</i>. </p><p>“The boss REMUNERATED our efforts with a large bonus.” </p><p>REMUNERATION is the act of REMUNERATING, or a payment, a recompense. “Art was troubled by his inadequate REMUNERATION and demanded more money.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: REMUNERATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "TIMOROUS": {
      "word": "TIMOROUS",
      "phonetic": "(tim'-ÔøΩ-as)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">fearful, timid, apprehensive </p><p>TIMOROUS comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">fear</i>, also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">timid</i>. A person who is TIMOROUS is easily intimidated and is afraid to do things, such as make decisions or be self-assertive. </p><p>“Paul grew so TIMOROUS once inside the deserted house that he couldn’t go forward or leave; he was frozen to the spot with fear.” </p><p>“The TIMOROUS clerk couldn’t get up the courage to ask his boss for a raise.” </p><p>“Susie is so TIMOROUS she is apprehensive about leaving the house.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">quiet</i>. TIMOROUS people are usually quiet, but TIMOROUS means <i class=“def-ital\">fearful</i>.</p>"
    },
    "CHURLISH": {
      "word": "CHURLISH",
      "phonetic": "(cher'-lish)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">rude, boorish, loutish </p><p>A CHURL was originally a man of the lowest class in England. The word then came to refer to a person having the qualities thought to be characteristic of a CHURL: rudeness, surliness, vulgarity. CHURLISH is the adjective from CHURL; see <i class=“def-ital\">-ish</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“The CHURLISH man refused to let the boys cut through his yard.” </p><p>“The CHURLISH waitress demanded to know if we hade made up our minds yet.” </p><p>“The bus driver CHURLISHLY told the children to shut up or get out and walk.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CHURL, n.</p>"
    },
    "DILATE": {
      "word": "DILATE",
      "phonetic": "(dl-lAt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to widen, expand </p><p>The <i class=“def-ital\">late</i> part of DILATE comes from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">wide</i>, also found in the English word <i class=“def-ital\">latitude</i>.  To DILATE is to become wider, to expand. The word is generally used about physical objects. </p><p>“The ophthalmologist put some drops in her eyes to make the pupils DILATE.” </p><p>The word is sometimes used about opinions or subject matter, with the meaning “to speak at length.” In this sense DILATE is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">on</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">upon</i>. “The senator DILATED upon his views on fiscal policy.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DILATION, n. DILATATION, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">di-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "HIATUS": {
      "word": "HIATUS",
      "phonetic": "(hl-A'-t::is)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a gap, interruption, break </p><p>A HIATUS is a gap or interval, generally of time or continuity. </p><p>“The celebrated actress returned to the stage after a HIATUS of twelve years.” </p><p>“During the brief HIATUS between appointments, the doctor was able to rest for a few minutes.” </p><p>“Students used the HIATUS between the end of classes and the beginning of exams to catch up on their reading.”</p>"
    },
    "LASSITUDE": {
      "word": "LASSITUDE",
      "phonetic": "(las'-ÔøΩtUd)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">weariness, lethargy, languor, listlessness </p><p>LASSITUDE is a state of weariness and inactivity, a lack of energy resulting from strain, overwork, a hot climate, or the like. </p><p>“Angela couldn’t seem to overcome her LASSITUDE; all she wanted to do was lie in bed.” </p><p>“After the long baseball season the player gave way to a strong feeling of LASSITUDE.” </p><p>“The muggy, tropical climate induced an overpowering LASSITUDE that made it difficult to work.”</p>"
    },
    "TRAVESTY": {
      "word": "TRAVESTY",
      "phonetic": "(pech'-U-1::int)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a false, absurd, or distorted representation of something; caricature </p><p>TRAVESTY comes from the Latin words <i class=“def-ital\">trans</i>, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">across</i>, and <i class=“def-ital\">vestire</i>, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">to clothe</i>. <i class=“def-ital\">Transvestite</i>, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">cross-dresser</i>, comes from these same roots. </p><p>“The newspaper article claimed that the botched legal proceeding was a travesty of justice.” </p><p>“Many people consider “The Book of Mormon” to be a brilliant travesty of religion.” </p><p>TRAVESTY can also be a verb meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">represent in a false or distorted way</i>. </p><p>“The students performed a skit travestying their drama teacher’s eccentricities.” </p><p>The most common wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">consequence</i>, perhaps because of confusion with <i class=“def-ital\">tragedy</i>.</p>"
    },
    "REVERIE": {
      "word": "REVERIE",
      "phonetic": "(rev'-::ir-E)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a daydream, fanciful musing </p><p>REVERIE is sometimes spelled REVERY. </p><p>A REVERIE is a daydream, a series of idle thoughts or images. </p><p>“Sharon was lost in a REVERIE, thinking about things that happened long ago.” </p><p>“Jim’s REVERIE lasted for an hour before he realized that he bad to go to work.” </p><p>It is also the act of daydreaming. </p><p>“The old man spent his days sitting by the lake in quiet REVERIE.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Prayer</i> is a popular choice as the meaning of REVERIE, perhaps because both involve a kind of quiet thought, perhaps because of confusion with the word <i class=“def-ital\">revere</i>, which means to <i class=“def-ital\">worship</i>.</p>"
    },
    "SAGACIOUS": {
      "word": "SAGACIOUS",
      "phonetic": "(sÔøΩgA'-shÔøΩs)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">shrewd, astute, judicious, wise </p><p>A SAGACIOUS person possesses good judgment, keen penetration, and farsightedness, usually obtained through wide experience. </p><p>“The SAGACIOUS lawyer said that these matters took time, but that we should win in the end.” </p><p>“Through her SAGACIOUS investments in computer stocks she managed to become quite wealthy.” </p><p>The noun related to SAGACIOUS is SAGACITY. </p><p>“Thanks to the SAGACITY of its president, this company has grown steadily over the years.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SAGACITY, n.</p>"
    },
    "DIRE": {
      "word": "DIRE",
      "phonetic": "(dlr)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">fearful, calamitous, disastrous; extreme, urgent </p><p>Something that is DIRE causes great fear, either because it is disastrous now, or threatens disaster in the future. </p><p>“The general warned of DIRE consequences if the country didn’t spend more money on defense.” </p><p>“The loss of the star center was a DIRE blow to the basketball team.” </p><p>Often the word places less emphasis on fear and more on urgency or desperation. </p><p>“Only in a DIRE emergency would a pupil be allowed to leave school early.” </p><p>“He was forced to steal out of DIRE necessity; otherwise he would have starved.”</p>"
    },
    "EBULLIENCE": {
      "word": "EBULLIENCE",
      "phonetic": "(i-bul'-yÔøΩns)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">enthusiasm, exuberance, high spirits </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">bull</i> part of EBULLIENCE comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">boil</i>. EBULLIENCE is a “boiling out” of enthusiasm or exuberance. It suggests an overflowing of feelings or high spirits. </p><p>“With his usual EBULLIENCE, the professor talked for an hour about how great and wise Socrates had been.” </p><p>The adjective from EBULLIENCE is EBULLIENT. </p><p>“After the victory, the EBULLIENT coach said that this was the finest team he had ever been associated with.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">brilliance</i>, perhaps because of the similarity in sound, and because both are positive qualities for a person to have. </p><p>Other forms of the word: EBULLIENT, adj.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    }
  },
  "id": "8",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "to QUAFF",
          "answers": [
            "eat",
            "laugh",
            "drink",
            "scratch",
            "cough"
          ],
          "word": "QUAFF",
          "correct": "drink"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHOLERIC",
          "answers": [
            "bad tempered",
            "dying",
            "passive",
            "energetic",
            "underfed"
          ],
          "word": "CHOLERIC",
          "correct": "bad tempered"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DULCET",
          "answers": [
            "boring",
            "sweet",
            "harsh",
            "bland",
            "smooth"
          ],
          "word": "DULCET",
          "correct": "sweet"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "stem",
            "helpful",
            "crafty",
            "fawning",
            "reverent"
          ],
          "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "correct": "fawning"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "to REMUNERATE",
          "answers": [
            "pay",
            "promote",
            "fine",
            "award",
            "recount"
          ],
          "word": "REMUNERATE",
          "correct": "pay"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TIMOROUS",
          "answers": [
            "nasty",
            "quiet",
            "loving",
            "tiny",
            "fearful"
          ],
          "word": "TIMOROUS",
          "correct": "fearful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHURLISH",
          "answers": [
            "helpful",
            "rude",
            "silly",
            "greedy",
            "ugly"
          ],
          "word": "CHURLISH",
          "correct": "rude"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "to DILATE",
          "answers": [
            "waver",
            "decline",
            "expand",
            "harden",
            "contract"
          ],
          "word": "DILATE",
          "correct": "expand"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HIATUS",
          "answers": [
            "problem",
            "shelter",
            "gap",
            "rumor",
            "extension"
          ],
          "word": "HIATUS",
          "correct": "gap"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LASSITUDE",
          "answers": [
            "poverty",
            "desire",
            "happiness",
            "greed",
            "weariness"
          ],
          "word": "LASSITUDE",
          "correct": "weariness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRAVESTY",
          "answers": [
            "duty",
            "caricature",
            "ceremony",
            "consequence",
            "characteristic"
          ],
          "word": "TRAVESTY",
          "correct": "caricature"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REVERIE",
          "answers": [
            "daydream",
            "prayer",
            "conversation",
            "task",
            "judgment"
          ],
          "word": "REVERIE",
          "correct": "daydream"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SAGACIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "absurd",
            "shrewd",
            "obscure",
            "courteous",
            "renowned"
          ],
          "word": "SAGACIOUS",
          "correct": "shrewd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DIRE",
          "answers": [
            "hideous",
            "uncertain",
            "complex",
            "complete",
            "fearful"
          ],
          "word": "DIRE",
          "correct": "fearful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EBULLIENCE",
          "answers": [
            "brilliance",
            "enthusiasm",
            "unhappiness",
            "fatness",
            "humor"
          ],
          "word": "EBULLIENCE",
          "correct": "enthusiasm"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can you QUAFF food?",
          "word": "QUAFF",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be fun to live with a CHOLERIC person?",
          "word": "CHOLERIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can DULCET sounds be soothing?",
          "word": "DULCET",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an argumentative person be OBSEQUIOUS?",
          "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would workers be angry if they received no REMUNERATION?",
          "word": "REMUNERATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are boxing champions usually TIMOROUS?",
          "word": "TIMOROUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do CHURLS tend to be pleasant?",
          "word": "CHURLISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can your stomach DILATE?",
          "word": "DILATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a HIATUS last for a long time?",
          "word": "HIATUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a boring job cause LASSITUDE?",
          "word": "LASSITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a TRAVESTY be jocose?",
          "word": "TRAVESTY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a REVERIE loud?",
          "word": "REVERIE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a SAGACIOUS person be likely to go bankrupt?",
          "word": "SAGACIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an earthquake in a populated area a DIRE event?",
          "word": "DIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would learning about a tragedy cause EBULLIENCE?",
          "word": "EBULLIENCE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "We didn't mean to be greedy, but the punch was so good we QUAFFED glass after glass of it.",
          "word": "QUAFF",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The doctor said the infant was CHOLERIC and had to be brought to the hospital immediately.",
          "word": "CHOLERIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The DULCET sounds of a jackhammer kept him from getting any sleep.",
          "word": "DULCET",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The OBSEQUIOUS doorman took off his hat and bowed to us as we went in.",
          "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jennifer REMUNERATED us that the party was Sunday night.",
          "word": "REMUNERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The TIMOROUS man always let other people get ahead of him in supermarket lines.",
          "word": "TIMOROUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The CHURLISH ballplayer snarled at the boys asking for his autograph.",
          "word": "CHURLISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The traffic jam DILATED John for his appointment.",
          "word": "DILATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The president-elect chose his cabinet during the three-month HIATUS between winning the election and taking office.",
          "word": "HIATUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They gave us extraordinary LASSITUDE, but we were still able to complete the job.",
          "word": "LASSITUDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The news headlines referred to the devastating earthquake as a TRAVESTY.",
          "word": "TRAVESTY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In solemn REVERIE he begged God to forgive his sins.",
          "word": "REVERIE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If it hadn't been for your SAGACIOUS advice we would have made some very foolish mistakes.",
          "word": "SAGACIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The book's DIRE forecasts of coming wars and famines were very depressing.",
          "word": "DIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Nothing could dampen their EBULLIENCE when the principal let them out of school early.",
          "word": "EBULLIENCE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "QUAFF",
          "answers": [
            "drink",
            "dine",
            "gulp"
          ],
          "word": "QUAFF",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHOLERIC",
          "answers": [
            "pugnacious",
            "frightened",
            "peevish"
          ],
          "word": "CHOLERIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DULCET",
          "answers": [
            "harsh",
            "tuneful",
            "melodious"
          ],
          "word": "DULCET",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "slavish",
            "secretive",
            "subservient"
          ],
          "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMUNERATE",
          "answers": [
            "recompense",
            "rectify",
            "reimburse"
          ],
          "word": "REMUNERATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TIMOROUS",
          "answers": [
            "frightened",
            "vexing",
            "daunted"
          ],
          "word": "TIMOROUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHURLISH",
          "answers": [
            "brusque",
            "dour",
            "suspicious"
          ],
          "word": "CHURLISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DILATE",
          "answers": [
            "expand",
            "widen",
            "shorten"
          ],
          "word": "DILATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HIATUS",
          "answers": [
            "interval",
            "conclusion",
            "intermission"
          ],
          "word": "HIATUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LASSITUDE",
          "answers": [
            "depression",
            "tiredness",
            "listlessness"
          ],
          "word": "LASSITUDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRAVESTY",
          "answers": [
            "mockery",
            "burlesque",
            "disaster"
          ],
          "word": "TRAVESTY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REVERIE",
          "answers": [
            "thinking",
            "planning",
            "dreaming"
          ],
          "word": "REVERIE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SAGACIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "holy",
            "shrewd",
            "wise"
          ],
          "word": "SAGACIOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DIRE",
          "answers": [
            "favorable",
            "ominous",
            "painful"
          ],
          "word": "DIRE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EBULLIENCE",
          "answers": [
            "exuberance",
            "contentment",
            "happiness"
          ],
          "word": "EBULLIENCE",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}